--== 本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品 ==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制｜阿凡提　　字幕调校｜Mivaner　　招募Q号｜324446465
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
♫ 尊贵的上帝 ♫
♪ Precious Lord ♪
♫ 牵着我的手 ♫
♪ Take my hand ♪
♫ 引我向前 ♫
♪ Lead me on ♪
♫ 扶我站立 ♫
♪ Let me stand ♪
♫ 我累了 ♫
♪ I am tired ♪
♫ 我无力 ♫
♪ I am weak ♪
烈血大风暴
♫ 我疲倦 ♫
♪ I am worn ♪
♫ 穿过风暴 ♫
♪ Through the storm ♪
♫ 透过黑暗 ♫
♪ Through the night ♪
♫ 引我向前 ♫
♪ Lead me on ♪
♫ 透过黑暗 ♫
♪ Through the night ♪
♫ 牵着我的手 ♫
♪ Take my hand ♪
♫ 尊贵的上帝 ♫
♪ Precious Lord ♪
♫ 引导 ♫
♪ And lead ♪
♫ 我回家 ♫
♪ Me home ♪
♫ 牵着我的手 ♫
♪ Take my hand ♪
♫ 尊贵的上帝 ♫
♪ Precious Lord ♪
♫ 引导 ♫
♪ And lead ♪
♫ 我回家 ♫
♪ Me home ♪
是什么？
What is it?
- 他们要怎样？ - 不知道
- What do they want?  - I don't know.
快开走吧
Just pass me.
快开走
Pass me.
- 是警察？ - 看不清楚
- Is it a cop?  - I can't see.
他们在玩什么游戏？
What the fuck are these jokers playing at?
你最好认为他们不是玩游戏
Oh, they ain't playing. You better believe it.
- 怎么办？ - 我不知道
- What are we gonna do?  - I don't know.
坐稳了 伙计们
Okay, hold on, you guys.
还有一辆卡车
There's a truck, too.
糟糕 是警察
Shit, it is a cop.
最好停车
You better stop.
坐着别动 伙计 别说话 让我来说
Okay, sit tight, you guys. Don't say anything. Let me talk.
好吗？没事的
All right? We'll be all right.
别怕
Just relax.
你以为这里能以任何速度驾驶吗？
Y'all think you can drive any speed you want around here?
吓死我们了 老兄
You had us scared to death, man.
别叫我“老兄” 犹太小子
Don't call me man, Jew-boy.
长官 我该怎么称呼你呢？
No, sir. What should I call you?
什么也别叫 你这个喜欢黑鬼的犹太小子 听着
You don't call me nothing, nigger-loving Jew-boy. You just listen.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
该死 有黑鬼的气息 犹太小子
Hell, you even starting to smell like a nigger, Jew-boy.
别怕 没事的
Take it easy. We'll be all right.
当然咯 黑鬼情人
Sure you will, nigger-lover.
他见了你的脸 这样不好 别让他见你的脸
He's seen your face. That ain't good. You don't want him seeing your face.
噢 这样就再没问题了
Oh, it don't make no difference no more.
妈的 快动手 小子
Oh, shit! We into it now, boys!
密西西比州　1964年
你只给我留下了个黑鬼
You only left me a nigger,
至少我射了黑鬼
but at least I shot me a nigger.
是的 的确
Yes, indeed.
♫ 听着 共产党人 黑人 犹太人 ♫
♪ Now listen, you communists and niggers and Jews ♪
♫ 叫你的伙伴散布消息 ♫
♪ Tell all your buddies to spread the news ♪
♫ 判决即将来临 ♫
♪ Your day of judgment will soon be nigh ♪
♫ 上帝的智慧至高无上 ♫
♪ As the Lord in His wisdom looks down from on high ♪
♫ 人种共存会使他丧失斗智？ ♫
♪ Will his battle be lost by mixing the races? ♪
♫ 我们要漂亮孩子 并非褐色面孔 ♫
♪ We want beautiful babies not ones with brown faces ♪
♫ 我说 绝不 绝不 ♫
♪ Never, never, never I say ♪
♫ 因为三K党绝不会持久 ♫
♪ For the Ku Klux Klan is here to stay ♪
♫ 我说 绝不 绝不 ♫
♪ Never, never, never I say ♪
♫ 因为三K党绝不会持久 ♫
♪ 'Cause the Ku Klux Klan is here to stay ♪
对三K党徒与其用吟唱 还不如用绞刑
These Ku Kluxers are better with lynchings than they are with lyrics.
安德森先生 看看那文件 我又没有做表演
Just read the file, Mr. Anderson. I can do without the cabaret.
老大 你不太喜欢我
You don't like me much, do you, boss?
我当然喜欢你
Sure I like you.
只是难赞同你的幽默感
I just don't share your sense of humor.
有时你赞同
Sometimes that's all you got left.
在局里多久了？
How long have you been in the bureau?
三年
Three years.
直接从大学来的？
Right out of college, huh?
不 从司法部来
No. From the Justice Department.
肯尼迪男孩 我明白了
Kennedy boy. Now I see.
不 你不明白
No, I don't think you do see.
我们坦诚一点吧
Let's get this thing straight.
今年我没有丘疹 我每天早上刮脸
I haven't had a pimple in years. I shave every morning.
我自己去浴室
I even go to the bathroom by myself.
所以抛弃“老大”这鬼话吧
So you can quit this "boss" stuff.
我负责是因为我以前经手过
They put me in charge, because I've been through this before.
- 伯明翰？蒙哥马利？ - 牛津
- Birmingham, Montgomery?  - Oxford.
- 在旧密西西比州我和梅雷迪思一起  - 哦
- I was with Meredith at Ole Miss.  - Oh, yeah.
你的头被砖头打伤 因此提拔你
You got hit in the head with a brick, so they gave you a promotion, right?
不 是肩膀
No. Shot in the shoulder.
至少你活着 这很重要
Well, at least you lived. That's important.
不 梅雷迪思活着 那更重要
No, Meredith lived. That's what's important.
密西西比州欢迎您
怎么有四只眼睛还看不到？
What's got four eyes and can't see?
- 什么？ - 密西西比州
- What?  - Mississippi.
♫ 我说 绝不 绝不 ♫
♪ Never, never, never I say ♪
♫ 因为三K党绝不会… ♫
♪ Because the Ku Klux Klan is here to... ♪
小镇的大楼
Big building for a small town.
你们好
Howdy.
早上好
Good morning.
我叫艾伦·沃德 是FBI的一员
My name's Alan Ward. I'm with the FBI.
联邦调查局？
Federal Bureau of Integration?
你这付德性不象密探 是吗？
In that get-up, you ain't exactly undercover, are you, now?
我们要见斯塔基警长
We're here to see Sheriff Stuckey.
警长正忙着
Sheriff's right busy now.
等着吧 或许他有时间会回来
You'll have to wait or come back some other time.
我们等
We'll wait.
听着 没教养的蠢货
Listen to me, you backwoods shit-ass, you.
你有两秒钟叫警长出来
You got about two seconds to get the sheriff out here,
否则我踢破那该死的门
or I'm gonna kick the goddamned door in, okay?
看来我们有客人
Well, hell, looks like we got some company.
有胡佛男孩来拜访
Some Hoover boys come down to visit.
- 有公干？ - 没错
- How you doing?  - Good.
- 我是斯塔基警长  - 鲁珀特·安德森
- I'm Sheriff Stuckey.  - Rupert Anderson.
- 鲁珀特 我们一直在期待你  - 哦
- Rupert? We been expecting you.  - Uh-huh.
见过我的副警长佩尔先生了
I assume you met my deputy, Mr. Pell?
当然
Sure did.
你们来此帮我们解决黑人问题？
You down here to help us solve our nigger problems?
不 是一宗失踪案
No. It's just a missing-person case.
额 好吧 走吧
Hmm. Well, come on.
你的伙伴就呆在此吧？
Say, you gonna want your boy in on this?
警长 我是特派密探沃德
Sheriff, I'm Special Agent Ward
我负责此案
and I'm in charge of this case.
我们认为案情可能比失踪者严重
We think it might be a little more serious than missing persons.
我不这么认为
I don't think so, boy.
知道我的看法吗？这是马丁·路德·金
In fact, you know what I think it is, it's a publicity stunt
之流的宣传伎俩
cooked up by that Martin Luther King fella.
走吧
Come on.
副警长佩尔说下午三时拘捕了三名超速行驶的男孩
At around 3:00 p.m., Deputy Pell says he arrested the three boys for speeding.
监禁到晚上十时释放了他们
He held them in jail until 10:00 p.m., and then released them.
他们开车离开
They drove off.
他说他跟随到县道
He says he followed them as far as the county line
再没有见过他们
and never saw them again.
他们为什么没打一个电话？
Why didn't they make a phone call?
他们为什么要打？
Why should they?
安德森先生 这些男孩是激进分子
Mr. Anderson, these boys were trained activists.
每个小时要报到
They're taught to check in every hour,
如果被捕 立刻会释放
and if they're arrested, the moment they're released from custody.
旅馆在监狱附近 可以去那打电话
The hotel is two minutes from the jail. They could have phoned from the lobby.
只是不能追踪
It just doesn't follow.
或许喝了啤酒
Maybe they went for a beer.
这些男孩不会
Not these boys.
罗斯维尔民权办公室开始打电话来说他们没报到
The civil rights office in Rossville started making calls as soon as they didn't check in.
这里的警长办公室说不知道那些男孩在哪里
The sheriff's office here said they had no idea where the boys were.
第一个谎言
First lie.
谁撒谎？警长办公室还是民权办公室？
By who? The sheriff's office or the civil rights office?
你相信谁？
Who would you believe?
沃德先生 我不了解你是否知道这个
Mr. Ward, I don't know if you knew it or not,
我要是小密西西比镇警长希望这样
but I was a sheriff in a little Mississippi town just like this.
就知道你这么说
Yes, I'm aware of that, Mr. Anderson.
说谎又不要本钱
Well, lying just don't come into it, you know?
我们离孟菲斯十英里
We were right on the border, 10 miles from Memphis,
离世界其它地方数百万英里
and a million miles from the rest of the world.
那么 既然一个镇的警长这么说
Now, if a sheriff in a little town like this says that's what happened,
那就这么咯
then that's what happened.
去吃点东西
Let's go eat.
我们现在客满了 您愿意等等吗？
We're full up right now, honey. Y'all wanna wait a while?
值得等等吗？
Is the wait worth it?
并不会白等的 等待时 看看菜单吧？
We're not full for nothing, sugar. Y'all want to look at a menu while you wait?
- 当然  - 谢谢
- Sure.  - Thank you.
打算如何？等待还是离开？
Well, what y'all gonna do, wait or leave?
我们等 因为我们想亲近你
We're gonna wait, Because we want to be near you.
那里有空位
There's some empty seats down there.
沃德先生
Mr. Ward.
那里有黑人 想都别想
That's the colored down there. Don't even think about it.
这里有人要离开了
There's some people over here getting ready to leave right now.
你不饿吗？安德森先生
Aren't you hungry, Mr. Anderson?
下午好 气色看起来不错
Good afternoon. Looks good.
介意问你几个问题吗？
Do you mind if I ask you a few questions?
我正在找一些资料
I'm looking for some information.
无可奉告 先生
I ain't got nothing to say to you, sir.
只是几个问题
Just a few questions.
无可奉告 先生
I ain't got nothing to say to you, sir.
三个民权男孩来这里
Three civil rights boys came here
建议设立选民注册所
to propose setting up a voter registration clinic.
在当地居民赞成之前 三K党将其烧毁了
Before the locals got a chance to say yes, the Klan burned them down.
你让某个人表决 但是他不能表决
Give a man a vote, but don't let him use it.
那是操作程序
Wekk, that's the way it works.
罗斯维尔办公室怎么说？
What'd their office in Rossville have to say?
他们证实那些男孩回到这里向会众道歉
They confirmed that the boys came back here to apologize to the congregation.
对不起 你们没有表决权
Sorry you folks didn't get to vote.
我想大家从来不知道你们甚至有权
I suppose most of you never knew you even had one.
现在 你们没有地方做礼拜了
Now you got no place to go on Sunday.
显然 他们回到这之后 与沿途的居民有交谈
Apparently, after they came back here, they talked to some locals down the road.
我们应该从这里入手
I think that's where we should start.
嗯 你可以问问你他们 但他们不会说的
Well, you can talk to them, but they won't talk to you.
我们走后 这些人还得在这里生活
These people have to live here long after we're packed up and gone.
他们宁愿忍住不说 也不会告诉我们
They'd rather bite their tongue off than talk to us.
按局程序 安德森先生
Bureau procedure, Mr. Anderson.
教堂着火 而你跑回家 是这样吗？
The church caught fire and you ran home, is that correct?
是的
Yes, sir.
四个白人阻止你？
And then the four white men stopped you?
是的
Yes, sir.
这四个白人打你丈夫？
And these four white men attacked your husband?
是的
Yes, sir.
你不认识他们
But you can't identify them?
不认识
No, sir.
你把这报告给警察了吗？
Did you report this to the police?
没有
No, sir.
但你告诉民权男孩发生了什么？
But you told the civil rights boys what happened?
是的
Yes, sir.
夫人 他们说了要去那里吗？
Madam, did they tell you where they were going after that?
没有
No, sir.
什么也没有说？
Nothing?
没有
No, sir.
好的 谢谢 夫人
All right. Thank you, Madam.
别客气
You're welcome.
快点
Come on, boy.
开门
Open up.
你哥哥霍利斯在吗？
Your brother Hollis here?
在
Yes, sir.
叫他起来 我们要见他
Well, wake his ass up. We want to see him.
- 为什么？ - 叫他起来
- Why?  - Just wake him up, boy.
怎么了？发什么了什么？
Why? What's the matter?
你在呀
There you are!
来这里
Come here, boy!
霍利斯
Hollis!
回来 他妈的黑鬼
Get your ass back here, you fucking nigger!
霍利斯 霍利斯
Hollis! Hollis!
混蛋
Shit!
最好别让我们看到你和FBI说话
We better not catch you talking to the FBI.
否则你死定了
You'll be dead, boy.
你同情这些孩子？
You admire these kids, don't you?
你不吗？
Don't you?
我想他们是被利用了
I think they're being used.
他们被大众车送到这里 一群混蛋
I think they're being sent down here in their Volkswagens and their sneakers,
打爆了他们的头
just to get their heads cracked open.
你可曾想到或许他们坚信他们做的？
Did it ever occur to you that maybe they believed in what they were doing?
他们想过最终会死吗？
Did it ever occur to them they were gonna end up dead?
也许吧
Maybe.
在华盛顿 他们肯定就知道
In Washington they sure as hell knew, didn't they?
有一些事值得为之去死
Some things are worth dying for.
这里的人们领会有点不同
Down here they see things a little differently.
他们认为值得为一些事去杀人
People down here feel some things are worth killing for.
这一切仇视从何而来？
Where does it come from, all this hatred?
你知道 我还是小孩时
You know, when I was a little boy,
一个名叫门罗的黑人老农住在我们街的另一头
an old Negro farmer lived down the road, name of Monroe.
他是…
And he was...
我想他只比我父亲运气好一点
I guess he was a little luckier than my daddy was.
他买了一头骡子
He bought himself a mule.
这是那个镇周围的一笔大交易
That was a big deal around that town.
我父亲讨厌那头骡子
My daddy hated that mule.
因为他的朋友骗他说
Because his friends were always kidding him about
看到门罗用骡子耕地
how they saw Monroe plowing with his new mule.
既然有一头骡子 门罗打算租另一块地
And Monroe was gonna rent another field now that he had a mule.
一天早上骡子死了
One morning that mule just showed up dead.
他们在水里下毒
They poisoned the water.
打那之后 我父亲再没提过那头骡子
And after that, there was never any mention about that mule around my daddy.
从来没再提过
Just never came up.
一次我们沿街开车
So one time, we were driving down the road,
经过门罗的地方 那里空荡荡的
and we passed Monroe's place and we saw it was empty.
我想他刚收拾行李离开了吧 去北边或其他地方
He just packed and left. I guess gone up north or something.
我一看父亲的脸
I looked over at my daddy's face
就知道是他干的
and I knew he'd done it.
他也清楚我知道 他很羞愧
He saw that I knew. He was ashamed.
我想他很羞愧
I guess he was ashamed.
他看着我说
He looked at me and he said,
“儿子 要是不能优于黑人 还能优于谁？”
"If you ain't any better than a nigger, son, who are you better than? "
你认为那是理由吗？
You think that's an excuse?
这不是理由 这只是我父亲的故事
No, it's not an excuse. It's just a story about my daddy.
为此你离开了那里？
Where's that leave you?
如此充满憎恨的一个老人
With an old man that was just so full of hate
他不知道那是贫穷扼杀了他
that he didn't know being poor was what was killing him.
关掉灯 关掉灯
Get the light! Get the light!
你没事吧？
You all right?
他们知道我们在这里
I guess they know we're here.
现在你知道你到了什么地方
Now you know what you're getting into.
我会与华盛顿联系 请求派更多的密探
I'm gonna call Washington. I need more agents.
我说这是错误的做法 你会改变主意吗？
Would it make any difference if I told you that's exactly the wrong thing to do?
不会
No.
整个地方一个月七十五元
The whole place for 75 a month.
这是个私人场所 在镇中心 是个很好的地方
It's private, it's central, it's perfect.
能容纳一百多个密探 或许两百个
There's room for 100 more agents. 200, maybe.
如果加上楼座
More on the balcony.
安德森先生 我们在找三个男孩
We're trying to find the three boys, Mr. Anderson.
我会接受一切能得到的帮助
I'll take all the help I can get.
这机遇何时开始的？
When's the show start?
是谁？
Who's the big shot?
三K党
That's the Klans.
没有尖帽子 却有许多的尖头
No pointy hats, but plenty of pointy heads.
我去查查车牌
Let me run a check on the plates.
下午好 先生们
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
安德森
Anderson.
来向市长提尔曼先生问候
Won't you say hello to our mayor, Mr. Tilman, here?
你好 安德森
How do you do, Anderson?
市长先生 理发师先生
Mr. Mayor, Mr. Barber.
看起来象一个地方
This looks like the place to be.
即使对我来说
Even for me.
没有比理发店更舒服的地方了
Nothing like a barber shop for jawing your socks off.
你从何处来？安德森
Where you from anyway, Anderson?
密西西比州桑顿市
Thornton, Mississippi, sir.
从田纳西州来只是胡说
Just a spit from Tennessee.
你必须懂得这里的规矩
Well then you must know how we all feel down here.
我们不喜欢告诉外人我们怎样生活
We don't take to outsiders telling us how to live our lives.
我很乐意告诉你这里的黑人很快乐
And I'm here to tell you our nigras were happy,
直到那些披头族把事情搞得沸沸扬扬
till those beatnik college kids came down here stirring things up.
在这之前没有任何人抱怨
Before that, there wasn't anybody complaining.
没人敢吧
Nobody dared.
这里有一个真正平安的社区 安德森
We got a real peaceful community down here, Anderson.
他们就象其他民族 你要是逼得过分…
Of course they're just like any other folks, I reckon, and push them too far...
我估计会象三捆旧炸药
The way I figure it, it's like three sticks of old dynamite.
要是触发了 就得上街收尸
You shake it up, and we're gonna be scraping bodies off the street.
我只是来调查三个失踪的孩子 问一些问题
I'm just down here to investigate the missing three kids, ask some questions.
即使全部归结起来是肉汁
If this all boiled down to gravy,
也盖不住鸡油煎牛排
there wouldn't be enough to cover up a chicken-fried steak.
你要找的孩子？我敢跟你打赌
Them kids you're looking for? I'll just about bet you a shiny new dime
他们一定在芝加哥
they're sitting up in Chicago right now
喝着冰啤酒 笑着谈论
drinking a cold beer and having a big laugh
在这里引起的混乱
about all the commotion they've stirred up down here.
我当然希望如此
Well, I sure hope so.
你可以告诉你上司
You tell your bosses
人们有对南方的偏见
people got the wrong idea about the South.
你知道我指的是什么
You know what I'm talking about.
人人衣着褴褛 落后 文盲
Everybody running around ragged, backwards, illiterate,
一日三餐腌猪肉和玉米饼
eating sow-belly and corn pone three times a day.
安德森 简单的事实是我们有两种文明
Simple fact is, Anderson, we got two cultures down here.
白种人文明和有色人种文明
White culture, and the colored culture.
这一直存在
That's the way it always has been.
并且会永远存在
That's the way it always will be.
美国其他地方看不到
Rest of America don't see it that way, Mr. Mayor.
美国其他地方屁都没有
Rest of America don't mean jack shit.
你在密西西比州
You in Mississippi now.
这是肯定的
That's for sure.
理发师先生 比分多少？
What's the score, Mr. Barber?
圣·路易斯队领先 五比零
St. Louis on top, five to nothing.
哪一局？
What inning is it?
第七局末
Bottom of the seventh.
安德森 你喜欢棒球？
You like baseball, do you, Anderson?
嗯 我喜欢 你知道…
Yeah, I do. You know...
只有那时黑人在白人面前挥舞棍棒
It's the only time when a black man can wave a stick at a white man
不认为是暴乱
and not start a riot.
长官
Sir.
我们查过了车牌 是克莱顿·汤利
We checked on the plate, sir. Clayton Townley.
汤利 三K党白骑士团的大巫师
Townley. Grand Wizard of the White Knights of the Ku Klux Klan.
就是他 我们有此车的线索
That's him. Oh, and I think we have a lead on the car, sir.
旅馆的一个乔克托人知道在何处
A Choctaw on the reservation thinks he knows where it is.
我在等一个电话
I'm waiting for a call.
很好
Good.
下周二有约会吗？
You have your appointment next Tuesday, right?
到时见 再见
I'll see you then. Bye-bye.
你要去…
You gonna go to...
下午好 女士们
Afternoon, ladies.
能为你效劳吗？
Can I help you?
嗯 我告诉你 我只是… 我只是不喜欢这个发型 明白吗？
Well, yes, you can. I tell you, I just... I hate the way I look, you know?
你认为怎么样？烫发？还是漂白？
What do you think? A permanent wave, maybe, or a bleached job or something?
这看起来不错 在这里做的吗？
Now, that looks pretty good. Did you have that done in here?
不 是在杰克逊
No! Jackson.
假发是你唯一的指望
I think a wig's your only hope, hon.
你的脑袋不可能有更多选择
You ain't gonna be able to do much with that cue ball.
谢谢你
Thank you.
即使你要问一些问题 这就是你所听到的一切
If you wanna ask custom questions, this is where you'll hear it all.
事实上 我要问的是
Yeah, well, matter of fact, I do, you know.
嗯
Yeah.
我想知道刚刚驱车过去的那位先生
I was just wondering who that gentleman was that just drove in over there.
我知道那不是约翰逊总统
Now, I know that isn't President Johnson.
他是汤利 克莱顿·汤利
He's name is Townley, Clayton Townley.
你是FBI？
Are you one of them FBI gentlemen?
是的 夫人
Yes, Madam, I am.
那两个孩子要是死了 真令人惋惜
Well if you ask me, I think it's a shame those two kids are dead,
希望你找到他们
but I sure hope you find them.
谢谢 其实有三个孩子失踪 还有一个是黑人
Thank you. Actually, it's three kids that are missing. There is a colored kid also.
是否没有两个白人 你们就不会来？
Do you honestly think you people'd be down here at all, if it weren't for those two white boys?
- 也许不是 小姐  - 是夫人
- Maybe not, Miss  - Mrs.
她丈夫是佩尔 雷·斯塔基的副警长
Pell. Her old man's Ray Stuckey's deputy.
我单身
But I'm single.
快看 他们来了
Look out! Here they come!
霍利斯？
Hollis?
退后 让开
Get back. Move out of the way.
我们会照料 这是地方问题
We'll take care of this. It's a local problem.
我们会处理 不需要你们帮忙
We'll handle this! We don't need your damn help!
大街上有血不太好 电视新闻会怎么说？
It ain't right having blood on Main Street. How'd that look on TV news?
- 起来  - 我来扶
- Okay, easy.  - Get up.
好的 我扶住他了 我扶好了
Okay, I got him. I got him.
让开
Get out of the way, now.
他是那就餐者的孩子
That's the kid from the diner.
在你和黑人孩子交谈之前 要再三考虑
Now maybe you'll think twice before you talk to colored kids with an audience.
你知道图珀洛方面发来了消息
They're just sending a message from the big boss from Tupelo and you know it!
我知道 克莱顿·汤利 尖头的头目
I know it, yes. Clayton Townley, a chief pointy head.
没错 你怎么知道？
Yeah, that's right. How did you know?
有时也该按局程序 沃德先生
Bureau procedure, Mr. Ward. You ought to try it sometime.
我们会
We did!
我们找过那些孩子开的汽车
We found the car the kids were driving.
早上好
Good morning.
两个啤酒罐 一个可乐瓶 一个绿色塑料瓶
Two beer cans, a Coca Cola bottle, green plastic bottle,
一块烧毁的手表停在十二点四十五 一串钥匙
badly burned wristwatch stopped at 12:45, set of keys.
没有尸体
No bodies.
我要搜索该区
I want the entire area searched.
彻底的搜索
Every inch.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
这是一片大沼泽
It's a big swamp.
伯德先生 彻底搜索
Every inch, Mr. Bird.
他们绝对没有离开密西西比州
I guess they never left Mississippi.
他们死了
Yeah, they're dead. They're dead.
伯德先生
Mr. Bird!
什么事？长官
Yes, sir?
停车场有电话
There's a telephone back at the truck stop.
去那 打电话 给我叫一百多人来
Get to it, get on it and get me a hundred more men here by morning.
- 一百？ - 一百
- A hundred?  - A hundred.
要局里人吗？长官
What, Bureau people, sir?
我不管是否是军队
I don't care if it's the goddamn army!
我只要搜索整个沼泽
I want this entire swamp searched!
是 长官
Yes, sir.
沃德先生 别这样 你要发动一场战争
Don't do it, Mr. Ward. You'll just start a war.
我们来之前 就是一场战争了
It was a war long before we got here.
你也是
You too!
醒醒 起来
Wake up! Come on!
离开这里 黑鬼 快走
Get the fuck out of here, nigger! Go on!
长官
Sir?
警长确实不在现场
The sheriff's alibi is solid.
那时他与舅子和两个堂弟在玩扑克
He was playing poker with his wife's brother and two cousins.
多久？
The whole time?
三个小时 他输了十一块三毛八
No, for three hours. He lost $11.38.
还有件事
There's something else, sir.
汽车旅馆经理找我们的麻烦
We're having a little trouble with the motel manager.
什么麻烦？
What kind of trouble?
他要我们离开
He wants us out.
他说我们妨碍了他的生意
He says we're bad for business.
买下来
Buy it.
什么？长官
Sorry, sir?
买下来
Buy it!
汽车旅馆
The motel.
我能出多高的价？
How high can I go?
不惜一切
Whatever it takes.
今天在密西西比州杰瑟普县
Today in Jessup County, Mississippi,
在本周的暴行中
amidst the violence that has erupted here this week,
政府决定寻找
the eyes of the nation had been firmly fixed on the search
三个失踪的民权工作者
for the three missing civil rights workers.
我想这是一个大骗局
Well, I think it's all a big hoax.
要是在沼泽 就会找得到
But if they are in that swamp, then they asked for it.
海军预备队和FBI密探一起
Naval reserves have been brought in to join scores of FBI agents
寻找失踪者
in their search for the missing men.
他们有密谋
I think they planned the whole thing.
他们正在纽约嘲笑我们密西西比人
They're sitting up there in New York laughing at us Mississippi folks.
- 你认为是一个骗局吗？ - 是的
- You think it's a hoax?  - Yeah, I think so.
一个大的骗局 什么也找不到
I think it's a big hoax. They ain't gonna find nothing.
民权领袖对失踪者的下落乐观
Civil rights leaders here are still optimistic as to the men's young whereabouts,
而私下却忧心失踪者是否活着
but privately, there is mounting concern that they will ever be found alive.
他们在自找麻烦 我认为他们已经陷入麻烦了
They came down here looking for trouble and I think they found it.
新闻网马雷克·鲍伯比在密西西比州杰瑟普县报道
This is Marek Barlbobi, Network News, Jessup County, Mississippi.
我来告诉你 我告诉你他们应该做什么
I'll tell you what. I'll tell you what they ought to be doing.
我认为他们应该去加拿大寻找
They ought to be looking up there in Canada for them boys
而不是在我们这里的沼泽
instead of our swamps around here.
我还会告诉你些别的事情 我想这是NAAC的人
I'll tell you something else too. I think it's a publicity stunt
想入非非的表演
dreamed up by these NAACP people.
NAAC的人？
NAACP people?
是的 NAACP（全国有色人种协进会）
Yeah, NAACP.
知道代表什么吗？
I bet you're all wondering what it stands for.
代表着黑鬼 鳄鱼 猿 浣熊 负鼠
It stands for niggers, alligators, apes, coons and possums.
你有什么 你有你的NAACP（全国有色人种协进会）
Tell you what you got. You got your NAACP,
你有你的SNCC 你有你的COFO
you got your SNCC, you got your COFO.
你知道所有的混乱是什么吗？
You know what that mess is?
是胡说 你懂吗？
B-U-L-L-S-H-l-T. You got it?
警长 这会是一个联邦案件吗？
Sheriff, will this be a federal case?
有一天 我们不必说
One day there'll come a time when we won't have to say,
“早上好 警长先生”
"Good morning, sir, Mr. Sheriff."
或许那时我们不必说“斯塔基先生”
Maybe there'll come a time when we won't have to say, "Mr. Stuckey".
有一天 我们只说“斯塔基”或“警长”
One day there'll come a time when we just say "Stuckey" or "Sheriff".
有一天 警长甚至不是白人
And one day there'll come a time when the sheriff won't even be a white man.
你好
Hello.
是否能问你一些问题？
I wonder if I could ask you a few questions?
我不认为你会告诉我这是哪种花
I don't suppose you could tell me what kind of flower these are, could you?
我看这里到处都是…
I been seeing them all over the place here and...
从来没见过这么漂亮的植物
I never saw such a darn pretty plant.
叫瓶子草
They're trumpet pitchers.
瓶子草？
Trumpet pitchers?
真的美丽
They're beautiful. They really are.
气味不怎么样 但漂亮
They don't smell so good, but they're pretty.
很高兴与你谈话
It's nice talking to you.
很抱歉打断你们的聚会
Sorry about interrupting your meeting here,
可没有人愿与我们交谈
but we can't seem to get anybody to talk to us.
象我妈妈往常说的 他们封嘴了
They just zip up, like my mama used to say.
人们不想和你交谈
The reason people don't wanna talk to you
是因为害怕涉及法律
is because they're afraid it'll get back to the law.
我们就是法律
We are the law.
你们不是这里的
Not around here, you ain't.
我们来查那些男孩出了什么事
We were sent here to find out what happened to those three boys.
他们是来这里帮你们的
They were here to help you.
你们不应该和有色人交谈
It ain't colored floks you should be talking to.
该和谁交谈呢？
Who should we be talking to?
走吧 亚伦
Come on, Aaron.
你们应当去警长办公室
You should start with the sheriff's office.
你为什么不害怕？
Why ain't you afraid?
为什么你不害怕？
How come you ain't?
亚伦
Aaron.
亚伦 走吧
Aaron, come on, son.
投球 迅速一击 直球安打
Here's the pitch. Swing and a line-drive base hit!
一人回本垒
Another runner's home!
下个投手是鲍勃·吉布森 他有点紧张
On to the next pitch by the ruffled Bob Gibson. He is upset.
罗恩·亨特一垒打
Ron Hunt singled to center.
希克曼上了三垒 麦兹队赢得第二场
Hickman rounded third and scored the Mets' second run of the game.
亨特在一垒 麦兹队二比一领先
Hunt holds on at first, and the Mets now lead 2 to 1.
下一个上场的是乔·克里斯多夫
And the next one up there will be Joe Christopher,
他三击出局 高飞球被博耶接杀
who struck out and popped out again Boyer.
晚上好 佩尔太太 我是沃德密探 这是安德森密探
Good evening, Mrs. Pell. I'm Agent Ward. This is Agent Anderson.
我们是FBI 你丈夫在家吗？
We're with the FBI. Is your husband home?
我们想和他谈谈
We'd like to have a word with him.
进来吧
Y'all come in, then.
克林顿 FBI要问你一些问题
It's the FBI gentlemen, Clinton. They wanna ask you some more questions.
我把你的晚餐放到烤炉去？
You want me to put your dinner in the oven?
你去忙吧
Leave us alone.
介意我坐一坐吗？
Mind if I take a seat?
什么该死的事要在家里打扰我？
What's so goddamn important you gotta bother me at home?
只是想再要你谈谈
Well, I just wanted to run through, once again,
六月二十一日的事
your movements on June 21 st.
六月哪天？
June which?
六月二十一日
June 21st.
现在 我们彼此心知肚明
Now, deputy, we both know what day we're talking about.
所以要开诚布公 然后你看你的球赛
So let's be civilized and the sooner you can get back to your ball-game
我们就可以回华盛顿
and we can get back to Washington.
我没打扰你吧
Please, don't let me interrupt you.
一个问题被问十几遍
It's just that when you've heard a question
是有点令人厌烦
asked a dozen times, it gets kind of boring.
是的 我同意
Yeah, I guess so.
你们不一同吃吗？
You don't eat together?
他工作时间不定
He works funny hours.
你觉得奇怪吗？
You think that's odd?
不…
No. No...
我自己就这样
I work funny hours myself.
我饿了 就吃 他饿了 他就吃
I eat when I'm hungry, he eats when he can.
- 要来点什么吗？ - 不 谢谢
- Can I get you something?  - No, no, thanks.
这房子不错 在这里生活多久了？
This is a nice house. How long have you lived here?
我在这里出生
I was born here.
很久以前我父亲玩扑克游戏输掉了这房子
But my father lost the house in a poker game one night a long time ago.
从那以后我们一直支付房租
We've been paying rent ever since.
那是一种邪恶的游戏
It's a wicked game.
扑克
Poker.
是邪恶的
Wicked.
安德森先生
Mr. Anderson?
很高兴与你谈话 我得走了
It was nice talking to you. Guess I gotta go.
肉排还热吧？宝贝 拿一瓶啤酒来
Them pork chops still any good, honey? Bring me a beer, will you?
晚安
Good night.
去看你的棒球吧 你知道他们在说什么 是吧？
Let's get back to baseball. You know what they say, don't you?
那是黑人能挥动棍棒的唯一比赛…
It's the only game where a black man can wave a stick and...
我知道 我已经听说了
I know that. I already heard that one.
五十分钟不在现场的证明取决于他的妻子
50 minutes of his alibi hinges on his wife.
你和她谈过 她怎么样？
You talked to her. What's she like?
她是一个好女人
She's a nice lady.
安德森先生 一个女人怎么这样结局…
Tell me, Mr. Anderson, how does a woman like that end up...
与一个混蛋一起？
With Shithead in there?
你知道这些小镇象什么
You know these small towns are like.
一个女孩在高中花费所有时间
A girl spends her entire time in high school
寻找她要嫁的人
looking for the guy she's gonna marry,
花费她的有生之年想知道为什么
then spends the rest of her life trying to figure out why.
也许错了 他过分自信
There's something's too wrong with him. He's too confident.
- 你看到了结婚照片？ - 没有
- Did you see the wedding photograph?  - No.
三个迎宾朋友用拇指钩住腰带
His three pals are ushers, they had this way of hooking their thumbs in their belts
三个手指尖向下
with the three fingers pointing down like that.
是什么呢？共济会会员特征吗？
So, what is that? Some sort of Masonic thing?
不
No!
是KKK
KKK.
我知道你没醉 我不想和你吵
I know you ain't drunk. I ain't gonna argue.
- 我没醉  - 你没醉
- I'm not drunk.  - All right, you ain't drunk.
我只是带你到睡觉的地方去
I'm just gonna take you where you can sleep it off.
好吧 站稳
All right, hold up.
- 谁在开车？ - 小心头
- Who's driving?  - Watch your head.
噢
Hi.
有几件事情需要和你谈谈
There was a couple things I need to check with you.
我丈夫不在家
My husband's not here.
实际上 我是想和你谈谈
Well, actually, it was you I wanted to talk to.
- 和我？ - 是的
- Me?  - Yeah.
好吧 你进来吧
Okay. Well, you better come in, then.
只一会儿
Just take a minute.
我的上司有点讨人厌 大学生嘛
My boss, he's kind of a pain. You know, the college kid.
一板一眼 循规蹈矩
He has to dot all the I's and cross all the T's.
你要问我什么呢？
What is it you want to ask me about?
这是一个跟时间有关的问题
Well, it's a time type thing.
一些事情我们还没弄清楚…
A couple of things we're just not clear about...
应该把你的花放到水里吗？
Wouldn't it be better if I put your flowers in some water while you're here?
其实是给你的
Yeah. Well, actually, they're for you.
很漂亮
They're beautiful.
是很漂亮
They are pretty, aren't they?
气味不怎么样 但漂亮
They don't smell so nice, but they're pretty.
来点什么吗？茶？
Can I get you anything? Would you like some tea?
嗯 谢谢
Yeah, I would. Thanks.
噢 别看那 一张糟糕的照片
Oh, don't you look at that. It's a terrible photo.
我可不这么认为
Oh, I don't know about that.
是最近的吗？
Is this recent?
不 我也希望
No. I wish.
对我而言是新近的
Well, this sure looks recent to me.
我们十四年前结的婚
We were married 14 years ago.
开玩笑吧？不… 别逗了
Are you kidding me? No, that... Come on!
要加糖吗？
You take sugar?
当然要
Sure do.
我是在象这样的镇子长大的
You know, I grew up in a town like this.
你很聪明 所以走了
You were smart enough to leave.
你为什么不走呢？
Why didn't you?
“无所谓了”
"For better or for worse."
你怎么样？结婚了吗？
How about you? Are you married?
两次
Two.
结过婚 据我记忆
Well, I was, as I remember.
没有持续很久 我从未回家
It didn't last very long. I was never home.
她厌倦了迈阿密的电话
I guess she got fed up with phone calls from Miami
和得梅因的明信片
and postcards from Des Moines.
周围总有某个小伙子
There was always a guy around.
有时间看电影或喝啤酒
Any guy that could spare the time for a movie or a beer
或随自动唱机的音乐跳舞
or a quarter for the jukebox.
她离开了
She left.
你怎么样？
How about you?
安德森先生 你了解南方
Oh, you know the South, Mr. Anderson.
高中毕业后嫁给第一个使你微笑的男孩
You leave high school, marry the first boy that makes you laugh.
你丈夫是相当不错的小伙子
Your husband's quite a guy.
我上司说大约有一个小时
You know, my boss has this thing about an hour,
准确的说是五十分钟 你丈夫说他和你在一起
50 minutes to be exact, that your husband says that he's with you.
我想是的
And I guess he was.
我想是
Guess he was.
真遗憾
Well, that's a pity.
这意味着我没有借口赖在这里了
Because that means that I don't have an excuse for hanging around here anymore.
嗯…
Well...
感谢你的冰镇茶
Thank you for the iced tea.
感谢你给的鲜花
Thank you for the flowers.
当然
Sure.
你知道是哪种花吗？
Do you know what kind they are?
听说叫瓶子草
A fellow told me they're called trumpet pitchers.
没错
Oh, that's right.
我父亲称它是地狱女人 因为它们…
My daddy used to call them "ladies from hell", because they're car...
食虫
Carnivorous.
- 就这样？ - 嗯
- That's the word?  - Yeah.
漂亮的颜色是诱饵
You see, that pretty color's the bait.
昆虫只要进入就会死亡
Insects just home on in, and, wham, they're dead
即使他们尽力逃脱
even before they got their shoes off.
或许我应摘别的东西
Maybe I should've picked something more appropriate.
或许
Maybe.
♫ 歌颂耶稣非凡的爱 ♫
♪ Sing the wondrous love of Jesus ♪
♫ 歌颂他的怜悯与恩典 ♫
♪ Sing his mercy and his grace ♪
♫ 在居所 光明与祝福 ♫
♪ In the mansions, bright and blessed ♪
♫ 为我们找到栖息之地 ♫
♪ He'll prepare for us a place ♪
♫ - 那将是欣喜之日  - 那将是 ♫
♪  - Day of rejoicing that will be.  - That will be ♪
♫ 我们看到耶稣之时 ♫
♪ When we all see Jesus ♪
♫ 我们唱歌 欢呼胜利 ♫
♪ We'll sing and shout the victory ♪
圣灵的和平和喜悦与你们同在
May the peace and the joy in the Holy Ghost
无论现在和永远 阿门
abide with all of you for now and forever. Amen.
♫ 我们到达天堂之时 ♫
♪ When we all get to heaven ♪
♫ 多么欣喜之日 ♫
♪ What a day of rejoicing ♪
♫ 那将是 ♫
♪ That will be ♪
♫ 我们看到耶稣之时 ♫
♪ When we all see Jesus, Jesus ♪
♫ 我们唱歌 欢呼胜利 ♫
♪ We'll sing and shout the victory ♪
黑鬼 已警告过你
You already been told once, nigger!
不必再警告你了
Now we don't want to have to tell you again!
你会有更多的麻烦
You go making any more trouble
向联邦的人多嘴
or flapping them bootlips off to any of them federal men,
我们一定会把你埋了
and we sure as hell gonna have to put you in the ground, boy.
决不会有松树箱
And that's without a pine box!
明白吗？
You understand me? !
在密西西比州如何对待黑人？
How do you think the Negroes have been treated here in Mississippi?
要公平对待 理应受到应有的对待
They're treated about fair. About as good as they ought to be.
很长时间以来黑人在这里受着可怕的对待
If you ask me, the niggers around here have been treated bad for a long time.
我认为马丁·路德·金是领导者之一
Again, I think Martin Luther King's one of the leaders.
J·埃德加·胡佛说他是一个共产主义者
I mean, J. Edgar Hoover said that he was a Communist.
并已证明了这一点 但我不知是否真实
And they had proof to that effect, but, you know, I don't know that for sure.
我没亲自看到 是他们说的
I hadn't seen it myself, but that's what they say.
你真的希望找到那黑人吗？
Hey, you really wanna find that nigger?
他们说要我们与黑人吃在一起 使用相同的浴室
They say we've got to eat together and use the same bathrooms as the niggers.
密西西比人很难做到
That's awfull hard for some Mississippi folks to do.
他们不喜欢我们 他们不洗澡 有股恶臭
They're not like us. They don't take baths. They stink.
他们… 他们有点下流
They... They're nasty.
他们不喜欢白人
They just not like white folks.
你认为那三个男孩会怎样？
What do you think has happened to the three boys?
死了
Dead.
就当他们死了
Just as dead as they can be.
这感觉真好
Feels so good.
她睡了吗？
Is she asleep? Is she?
很抱歉 吵醒你了
I'm sorry I woke you up.
再见 我要出去几个小时
Bye, hon. I'm gonna be a couple hours.
好的
All right.
玛莉 那是贝齐的孩子吗？
Well, Mary, is that your Betsy's kid?
是的 她长的真快 是吧？
Yeah, she's growing up real quick, isn't she?
好了
Come on.
玛莉 到星期二就好了
Tuesday will be just fine on those, Mary.
有趣
Funny.
他们的孩子都那么可爱
Their kids are so cute.
- 我们走吧  - 那事能靠我吗？
- Here we go.  - Is that thing back on me again?
整个特勤处都保护不了总统
If the entire Secret Service couldn't protect the president of the United States,
我们又怎能保护一些黑人？
how on the hell are we supposed to protect a few nigras?
我再说一次 并非没什么
I'm telling you again, it ain't nothing but
只是一些下层白人喝了太多廉价酒
a bunch of low-life white trash drinking too much cheap alcohol.
更象天拿水和蛇汁 因为口感象马丁尼酒一样
More like paint thinner and snake juice, because this state's as dry as a martini.
一些酒鬼可以证明这一点
And we got the alcoholics to prove it.
劳驾 请让个地方 劳驾 鲍勃
Excuse me. Give me a little room here. Excuse me. Excuse me, Bob.
- 行吗？ - 请问你的名字？
- Is this okay?  - Your name, please?
克莱顿·汤利 当地商人
Clayton Townley, local businessman.
你是三K党白骑士团的发言人？
Are you, sir, a spokesman for the White Knights of the Ku Klux Klan?
我告诉你 我是商人
I told you. I'm a businessman.
我也是一个密西西比人 一个美国人
I'm also a Mississippian and an American.
我和许多密西西比人都讨厌
And I'm getting sick and tired of the way many of us Mississippians
报纸和电视在歪曲我们的看法
are having our views distorted by you newspaper people and on the TV.
所以我们很坦率
So let's get this straight.
我们不接受犹太人 因为他们拒绝基督
We do not accept Jews, because they reject Christ.
他们对国际银行业联盟的控制
And their control of the international banking cartels
实质是共产主义
are at the root of what we call Communism today.
我们不接受罗马公教徒 因为他们屈服于罗马独裁者
We do not accept papists, because they bow to a Roman dictator.
我们不接受土耳其人 蒙古人 鞑靼人 东方人
We do not accept Turks, Mongols, Tartars, Orientals now Negroes,
我们在这里保护
because we're here to protect
盎格鲁撒克逊人的民主政治以及美国人的方式
Anglo-Saxon democracy and the American way.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
你是亲属间不应该有性关系的活证据
I swear to God, Lester, you are living proof that cousins shouldn't fuck.
我是说 这个有色男孩
What I was trying to say, there's this colored boy.
他想参加阿拉巴马州贝尔·布莱恩特的橄榄球队
He wants to play football for Bear Bryant over at Alabama.
贝尔说“我给你一次尝试的机会”
So Bear says, "I'm gonna give you a tryout."
他拿着什么跑呢？一个西瓜吗？
What's he gonna run with, a watermelon?
他还在继续跑
And he's gonna keep on running too.
他说“你去球门线那里”
He says, "Okay, boy, you get down there on one goal line."
他要整个队去另一球门线 整个队
He puts the whole other team on the other goal line. Whole other team!
把球扔给男孩说…
He throws the boy the ball and he says...
营业吗？
Are you open?
你会是一名成员 在这喝酒
You gotta be a member to drink here.
一名成员？
Member?
什么成员？
A member of what?
社交俱乐部成员
Member of the social club.
我还以为你买啤酒给我
I thought you'd just buy me a beer.
弗兰克 给他一瓶啤酒
Give him a beer, Frank.
很高兴再次回到酒县
Nice to be back in a dry county again.
我当警长时 一半薪水
When I was sheriff, about half of my take-home pay
来自向这样非法的家族征收的税款
was from collecting taxes on illegal jukes like this.
大概这里也如此
Probably works the same here.
我想你也捞了一大笔钱 所以装作没看见走私贩
I was thinking you'd haul in a tidy penny here, winking at the bootleggers.
我对此并非一无所知
I know nothing about that.
嗯
Yeah.
一大笔钱
A tidy penny.
还有比这更烈的吗？副警长
You got anything stronger than this, deputy?
没有
No. No, we ain't.
哦 你知道的 在密西西比州桑顿市的每个院落都有酒
Oh! You know, in Thornton, Mississippi, there's a joy juice still in every yard.
只需要一些谷物和糖 用一只罐蒸煮就行了
Yeah, well, all you need is just some corn, sugar, and a pot to boil it in.
我曾试图找老仆人的手印
I tried to take the fingerprints of this old boy one time.
他的一生都交给了麦芽浆桶
And he had his hands in a mash barrel all his life.
那上面根本就没有手印
You know, there was no skin and all on there. There was no prints.
我们对密西西比老仆人的故事没兴趣 安德森
We ain't interested in your good old Mississippi boring stories, Anderson.
- 你在这里不会有更多收获  - 嗯
- You ain't from here no more.  - Mm-hm.
你为什么不走呢？
Why'd you leave, anyway?
我只是想看看风景 你知道…
Well, I just wanted a change of scenery, you know...
粗面粉使我口中带有一股怪味道
The grits started leaving a bad taste in my mouth.
FBI先生 你既然有如此感受
If that's how you feel about it, Mr. FBI man,
何不喝了这杯酒然后离开这里
why don't you drink up that beer and get the hell on out of here,
回北方去找钟情黑人和共产党人的上司？
and back to your Commie, nigger-loving bosses up north?
你一定不认识我的上司 胡佛先生
You must not know my boss, Mr. Hoover.
他不太喜欢共产党人 他会站在你这一边
He's not too fond of Commies. He'd be on your side there.
我不相信两个混蛋和你的胡佛先生立场相同
I don't give two shits whose side your Mr. Hoover's on, boy.
这个县有五千黑人没有做选民注册
All I konw is we got 5, 000 niggers in this county who ain't registered to vote yet.
我所关心的是他们永远也不会注册
And as far as I'm concerned, they never will.
去告诉你们华盛顿自负的上司
So you can tell your stiff suits up there in Washington, D.C.
他们绝对改变不了
that they ain't gonna change us one bit.
除非我死 或者大量黑人死亡
Unless it's over my dead body. Or a lot of dead niggers.
你会死？弗兰克 那是你的意思吗？
You'd kill, Frank? Is that what you're saying?
这是在扭猫的脖子 不要有更多的想法
I wouldn't give it no more thought than wringing a cat's neck.
密西西比州还没有法庭能证明我有罪
And there ain't no court in Mississippi that'd convict me for it.
怎么样？副警长 你怎么理解扭脖子？
How about you, deputy? How are you with wringing necks, huh?
你老是逼我 胡佛男孩
Just keep pushing me, Hoover boy.
你还真坦率 笨蛋
You get this straight, you fucker!
告诉你的变态上司
You tell your queer-ass nigger-bosses up north
在这里永远也找不到他们
they ain't never gonna find them civil righters down here.
因此你最好收拾行囊
So you might as well pack up your bags
滚回北方去
and head your ass back up on north where you belong.
你还真坦率 笨蛋
You get this straight, shitkicker!
别把我看扁了
Don't you go mistaking me for some whoever body.
你要是认为我们要消失 你就是脑残
You got brains in your dick, if you think we're just gonna fade away.
我们将待在这里直至这件事了结
We're gonna be here till this thing's finished.
怎么样？副警长
How about you, Deputy?
那支枪只是炫耀吗？
Is that gun just for show?
还是偶尔射过人？
Or do you get to shoot people once in a while?
谢谢啤酒
Thanks for the beer.
问问他们是否想保护这个国家
And ask them if they wanna help save this country
免于种族融合的混乱
from the onslaught of integration.
那种体制是想把白人儿童和有色人儿童
You know the system is they want to throw white children and colored children
植入种族融合的熔炉
into the melting pot of integration,
将来人种杂交
throughout of which will come a conglomerated
产生黑白混血儿
mulato, mongrel class of people!
种族将在这种运动中被毁灭
Both races will be destroyed in such a move.
除非上帝消逝 我将屈服
I, for one, under God will die before I'll yield one inch
美国的这种运动
to that kind of a movement in America.
你知道你引起的麻烦吗？
Do you know how much trouble you've caused?
他们整天在电台
They've been on the radio all day,
从汤利到州长 每一个人都在谈FBI威吓
everyone from Townley to the Governor talking about FBI intimidation.
安德森先生 我们不是暴徒 这件事要按我的方式办
We're not thugs, Mr. Anderson. We're gonna do this thing my way!
我知道 按局程序嘛
I know, bureau procedure.
你为什么在美容店？
And what the hell were you doing at the beauty parlor?
是局里的事 我应该知道
If that was Bureau business, I wanna know about it.
不是的话 我不允许 明白吗？
If it wasn't, I won't allow it. Do you understand me? !
进来
Get in here!
你知道你的问题吗？
You know what your problem is?
你不懂何时开口 何时闭嘴 这使你成了一个傻瓜
You don't know when to speak and when to shut up! That makes you a fool.
佩尔太太什么也不会说 她丈夫不想她说
Mrs. Pell ain't gonna say anything to me her husband doesn't want her to say.
我不会让她这么压抑
Now, I'm not gonna choke it out!
这个棘手的问题只可从内心入手
This can of worms only opens from the inside.
我知道
I know that.
自由
Freedom!
白人黑人
White nigger!
赶快
Hurry up!
自由 自由 自由
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
二十分？
20 cents?
自由 自由 自由
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
♫ 肩负 ♫
♪ Bring him ♪
♫ 你的重任 ♫
♪ Your burdens ♪
♫ 并非他的宠爱 ♫
♪ Seek not his favour ♪
♫ 向他… 向他倾诉你的痛苦 ♫
♪ Tell... tell him your sorrows ♪
- 喂  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey, now.
只是路过 来问声好
Just passing by, just saying hello.
你没去看游行？
You're not out watching the parade?
你怎么不问我问题？
Say, how come none of you guys didn't ask me any questions?
好像这这镇子的人都不和我谈
It seems everybody in town has been talked to except me.
你怎么不叫些英俊的FBI男孩来？
Why don't you send some of them good-looking FBI boys to talk to me?
很抱歉打扰了 我在五金商店…
Sorry about the intrusion. I was over at the hardware store and...
山核桃？
Pecan?
我讨厌山核桃
I'm sick of pecans.
自由 自由
Freedom!
你们决心起来抗争吗？
You willing to stand up and fight?
是的
Yes!
自由
Freedom!
平等
Equality!
你打算怎么查？
How'd you find out about this?
按局程序 沃德先生
Bureau procedure, Mr. Ward.
斯塔基警长
Sheriff Stuckey.
他有电话
He got his phone call.
真想知道是谁打的
Wonder who else was called.
你要去那里？
Where're you going, boy?
快走吧 快走吧 离开这里
Go on. Go on, get out of here.
他们来了
Here they come.
走吧
Come on. Let's go.
等他们回屋里
We'll wait until they go back inside.
抓住他
Get him!
把他弄上车
Get him in the truck now!
进屋里去呀 婊子养的
Get inside, you sons of bitches!
快点 走吧
Come on, let's go. Come on!
- 等他们回屋里  - 走吧 快点
- Wait until they go back inside!  - Let's go! Come on!
走吧 快点
Come on! Let's go! Come on!
快
Come on!
- 向左拐  - 你怎么知道？
- Turn left.  - How do you know?
我不知道 向左拐
I don't. Just turn left.
是那卡车
There's the truck.
上那条小路
Go up that little road there.
停车 停车 就停在这
Stop, stop. Stop right here.
这些人怎么了？
What's wrong with these people?
沃克太太 我知道你很为难 但我需要你的帮助
Mrs. Walker, I know this is difficult for you, but I really need your help.
你只要说服你儿子出来指控
If you could just persuade your son to press charges,
我们就能立刻拘捕副警长
then we could pick up the deputy at least right away.
他不会对任何人说
He won't talk to no one.
总之没有用的
And it won't do no good anyway.
我保证会拘捕
I promise it will.
别理他了
Leave him alone.
但愿也别打扰我们
Maybe then, they'll let us alone.
如果这是一个范例
If this is a pattern,
就能猜测六月二十一日发生了什么
I guess at least we know what happened on June 21st.
佩尔在下午三时扣留了三名超速行驶的男孩
Pell stopped the three boys for speeding at 3 o'clock.
将他们监禁 直到三K党组织好
He held them in jail until the Klan could get organized.
然后在十点半释放
Then he released them at 10:30.
那时 他的伙伴已在等待
And by that time, his buddies were ready and waiting.
不 那晚佩尔肯定去了
No, Deputy Pell went with them that night.
你认为他撒谎？
I'm sure of it. You think he'll crack?
人们说响尾蛇不会自取灭亡
Down here they say rattlesnakes don't commit suicide.
副警长佩尔 你放了三个民权工作者
Deputy Pell, did you release the three civil rights workers
交给三K党 就在六月二十一日晚上
into the hands of the Klan on the night of June 21st?
没有
No.
你是三K党成员吗？
Are you yourself a member of the Ku Klux Klan?
不是
No.
你曾经是吗？
Have you ever been a member of the Ku Klux Klan?
不是
No.
熟悉独眼巨人吗？
Are you familiar with the term Grand Cyclops?
听说过
I've heard of it.
事实上过去三年来 你是
Were you in fact the Grand Cyclops of the East Mississippi Klavern
三K党白骑士团的独眼巨人？
of the White Knights of the Ku Klux Klan for the past three years?
反对 我的委托人已说过他甚至不是三K党成员
Objection. My client's already told you he's not even a member of the Klan.
反对？这只是面谈 没有必要这么正式吧
Objection? This is just an interview, sir. There's really no need to be so formal.
只是面谈的话 我不必呆在这里 是吧？
Well, if this is just an interview, I guess I don't have to stay here, do I?
我有事要做
I got work to do.
我想你也有事要做？
I guess you do too, don't you?
没错 你相信我们会做
Yes, sir. And you can be sure that we'll do it.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你们要指控我 就知道去哪里查我
You get enough to indict me, you know where to find me.
- 怎么样？ - 没事
- How'd it go?  - Fine. It went just fine.
别担心那些该死的事
Don't you worry about a goddamn thing.
你会被指控吗？
Are you gonna be indicted?
FBI有指控警长办公室的证据吗？
Does the FBI have evidence that the Sheriff's office is invovled?
你与他们合作吗？
Are you cooperating in this investigation?
我们一惯合作
We're cooperating just like we have all along.
毫无证据可言
They have no damn evidence either. It's all circumstancial.
先生 请不要拍摄
Sir, could you not do that, please? Sir, do not do that, please!
已经告诉你了 现在 给我滚开
Don't you understand? Now, get the fuck out of here!
要告诉你两千次吗？
We have to tell you two thousand times?
从哪来滚哪去
Now get out of here and go back where you belong!
在我面前消失
Get out of my face, boy!
滚开 别打扰我们
Get on out and leave us alone!
别打扰我们
Leave us alone!
从哪来滚哪去 你找揍呀
Go on home where you belong! Boy, you're gonna get hurt now.
沃德先生 此事我们勉强能接受
Mr. Ward, this is getting to be just about as much as we can take.
可我无法表达更强的怨言
I cannot register my complaints more strongly.
现在无法 先生
Not now, sir.
现在 你只有一分钟
Now, you just a minute.
我对公众追逐我的警长处很不满意
I resent your public pursuit of my Sheriff's department.
你在竭尽所能将他们牵涉进这些失踪案
You have made every effort to implicate them in these disappearances.
含沙射影并不能证明
But your goddamn slimey innuendos are not evidence
他们涉及任何罪行
that they were any way connected with any crime.
我们正在设法发掘真相 但有阻碍
We're just trying to get to the truth. It's frustrating for us too!
任何傻瓜可以出来指控 沃德 但那不是证据
Anyone jackass can point a finger, Ward. Now, that ain't evidence.
在这里 旧棉花间苗机的使用者们还会蠢得去相信民主
Down here, us old cotton-choppers are still stupid enough to believe in democracy.
我们要懂得按法律行使权利
And you can rest assured, sir, we know our rights under the law!
你知道就好 我用一台棉花间苗机来打赌
You know something all right. I'll bet a cotton-chopping dollar on that.
你知道吗 安德森 你越来越咄咄逼人
You know what, Anderson? You're starting to get so far up my nose,
我开始觉得你在威胁我
I'm beginning to feel your boots on my chin.
我再次告诉你
And I'm telling you one more time, Mr. apple-red,
几个披着床单的疯子
a couple of crazies dressed in bed sheets
在乡下跳舞来吓唬黑人
dancing around the countryside scaring Negroes
不是整个密西西比州的错
is not the goddamn fault of the entire state of Mississippi!
我告诉你 提尔曼 有三个孩子死亡
I'm telling you, Tilman, there are three dead kids out there somewhere,
很多人害怕 这都是因为你的警长处
and a lot of scared people because of your goddamn Sheriff's department.
大家要相互体谅
So you better get used to having us around.
也体谅我威胁你
And you better get used to my boots on your chin too.
你们最好放弃
You people better back off!
该死的FBI 自以为是
Goddamn FBI! Just who on hell do they think they are?
敢来我的地盘…
Coming down on my part of the goddamn country harassing...
市长先生 你有要说的吗？
Do you have a statement, Mr. Mayor?
该死的我当然有
You got goddamn right I got a statement!
安德森先生 刚才
For a moment there, Mr. Anderson,
我们彼此立场相同
it sounded like we were both on the same side.
宝贝 你好吗？
Are you all right, honey?
我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
有什么就叫我
Let me know if you need anything.
谢谢 我会的
Thanks, I will.
妈妈 快来
Mama, Mama, come quick!
没有他的踪迹 他离开很久了
There's no sign of him, sir. He's long gone.
他母亲住在街对面 她可能不会开门
His mother, she lives across the street. She won't talk to us. Won't even answer the door.
我想整个区一定有人看见了
I want the whole area covered. Someone must have seen something.
他们不会说 先生
They won't talk to us, sir.
伯德先生 走吧 如果他们不说 就摆脱不了
Get going, Mr. Bird. If they won't talk to us, shake it out of them.
好吧 我们走 去每个住宅 快点
All right, let's go. Every house. Come on.
怎么？
What?
这些白人会四处销毁痕迹
Sending all these white guys chasing around these dog tracks with their little notebooks
你将一无所获
is gonna get you nowhere.
你能做什么？
Okay. What would you do?
可以害怕
It's okay to be afraid.
快点 威利
Go on, Willie.
告诉他们
Tell them what you saw.
被告站起来
The defendants will rise.
在这个国家 一个人的家就是他的避难所
In this country, a man's home is his castle.
那是这个社会生存的一个原则
That is one of the principles by which this community survives.
你们已经破坏了这个原则
You men have done violence to that principle.
但我要你们知道 法庭了解
But I want you to know that the court understands
你们已经犯的罪
that the crimes that you have comitted
至少在某种程度上
have been, to some extent at least,
是受外来影响
brought about by outside influences.
外人已经进入杰瑟普县 他们是道德卑贱的人
Outsiders have come into Jessup County and they've been people of low morality.
不洁净的人
And unhygienic.
他们的存在激怒了许多人
And their presence here has provoked a lot of people.
因此法庭了解 没有宽恕他们 请注意
So the court understands, without condoning them, mind you,
你们已经承认有罪的 至少在某种程度上
that the crimes to which you men have pled guilty were, to some extent at least,
是这些外来影响引起的
provoked by these outside influences.
鉴于所有一切 我将从轻处罚你们
So with all this, I'm gonna make your punishment light.
我打算判你们每人五年监禁
I'm gonna sentence you each to five years imprisonment.
但我要延缓判决
But I'm gonna suspend these sentences.
你们不能进去 先生
You can't go in there, sir.
FBI 让我们进去
FBI. Let us through.
抱歉 你们不能进去
I'm sorry, sir. You can't go in there.
警长
Sheriff!
你们真的在进行一些事
You started something this time.
车让开 我要进去和他们谈
Can you move these cars? I wanna go in there and talk to them.
你去 只要你能去
No, you're gone as far as you're gonna go.
我们能处理
This ain't nothing we can't handle.
只是一些疯狂的有色人挖开了自己的屁眼
Just a bunch of crazy coloreds tearing up their own assholes.
地方问题
Local problem.
沃德先生 瞧那火
Look at those flames, Mr. Ward.
那就是他们要你来的原因 是吗？
That's why they sent you down here, wasn't it?
你知道的 总之发生了
It would've happened anyway and you know it.
我要是黑人 我可能会用同样的方式
You know, if I was a Negro, I'd probably think the same way they do.
你要是黑人
If you were a Negro,
没人会在乎你的想法
nobody would give a damn what you thought.
亚伦 亚伦 起来
Aaron, Aaron, Aaron, get up!
带你妈妈 奶奶和孩子们从后门出去 听到了吗？
Take your mama, you grand-mama and the children out the back door. You hear?
离开后 就快走 明白吗？快走 儿子
When you hit the road, keep going. You understand? Keep going, son.
内森 快起来 内森 快起来 内森
Nathan! Come on, Nathan! Get up! Get up, Nathan, now!
快起来 下床
Come on! Get out the bed!
怎么了？
What's happening?
起来 妈妈 我们快走
Come on, Mama! Let's go! Come on, Mama!
你们快走
Come on, y'all!
快起来 孩子
Get up, child.
快走 奶奶
Come on, Grandma!
我们走
Let's go!
♫ 你们都辛劳 ♫
♪ All ye who labour ♪
是谁？
Who's there?
谁在那 出来 听到吗？
If you're in there, come on out. You hear?
我别无选择
I ain't taking this shit no more!
♫ 肩负你的重任 ♫
♪ Bring him your burdens ♪
♫ 并非他的宠爱 ♫
♪ Seek not his favour ♪
♫ 向他… 向他倾诉你的痛苦 ♫
♪ Tell... tell him your sorrows ♪
♫ 向… 他… 倾诉 ♫
♪ In... him... confide ♪
♫ 他满足 ♫
♪ He satisfies ♪
还好吧 爸爸
You'll be okay, Papa.
妈妈和女孩们都好
Mama and the girls are fine.
你的头受伤了
They just cracked your head some.
要保持呼吸 你别死
You just keep on breathing. Don't you go dying on me now.
听到吗？
You hear me?
你会没事的
You're gonna be just fine.
你看 母牛不会跑
You know, cows won't run away.
没人知道为什么 我想它们只是愚蠢
No one knows why. They're just stupid, I guess.
它们站那里直到吃饱喝足
They just stand there until their bellies swell up and they pop.
他们有亲戚在底特律
They have relatives in Detroit.
他们去哪里？
Are they gonna go?
我没给他们任何选择
I didn't give them any choice.
至少我们知道谁干的
At least, we know who did this.
是我们
We did.
别烦躁 会有进展
Don't fret. It's progress.
二十年前他们对偷西瓜的都要吊死
Twenty years ago, they'd strung them up for stealing watermelons.
我不明白 安德森先生 根本没有这种事
I don't understand you, Mr. Anderson. Not at all.
我们坦诚一点吧
Let's get something straight, all right?
此事情经新闻报道就被弄糟了
This whole thing was fucked up the moment we turned it into a show for the newsmen.
三个孩子失踪就是新闻
The moment these three kids disappeared, it was news.
三个民权工作者失踪就是新闻
The moment the three civil rights workers disappeared, it was news.
他们只是孩子 至今下落不明
To me they're just kids. They're still missing.
佩尔说跟他妻子一起五十分钟
What's missing is the 50 minutes Pell said he was with his wife.
行
Okay.
我爱密西西比州
I love Mississippi.
他们…
They...
他们不喜欢密西西比州
They hate Mississippi.
他们恨我们是因为我们做了
They hate us, because we present
种族隔离的辉煌典范
a shining example of successful segregation.
这些北方学生 与他们的无神论者 共产主义上司
These northern students, with their atheist, Communist bosses,
今年夏天进入我们社区妄图摧毁这个典范
that have come into our community this summer with the wish to destroy it,
本周已采取了可怕的打击
this week, have taken a terrible blow.
他们的企图破灭了
This week, their cause has been crippled.
本周 这些联邦警察在窥探我们的生活
This week, all of these federal policemen you see out here
侵犯我们公民的自由
prying into our lives violating our civil beliefs
据了解 他们无力反对我们
have learned that they are powerless against us,
每个盎格鲁撒克逊基督徒
if every single Anglo-Saxon Christian one of us
与我们站在一起
stands together!
本周…
This week...
- 沃德？ - 有客人
- Mr. Ward?  - We got company, sir.
你为何在此？这是政治性集会
You got no right to be here. This is a political meeting.
我并没感到这种气氛 副警长
Doesn't smell that way to me, Deputy.
这是政治性集会 胡佛男孩
It's a goddamn political meeting, Hoover boy!
是象政治性集会 但气氛更象三K党
Oh, it looks like a political meeting, but smells more like Klan to me.
不管有没有穿万圣节服装
With or without the Halloween costumes.
先生们
Gentlemen.
在密西西比州法庭 已经提醒他们
In the courts of Mississippi, they have been reminded
他们不能凭借武力将我们社区变成他们社区的摹本
that they cannot by force turn our communities into relicas of their communities.
社区里黑人闹事没受限制 没受处罚
Communities in which Negroes run riot, unrestrained and unpunished
今年夏天在哈莱姆街道
as they do this summer in the streets of Harlem,
奥克兰街道
or they do in the streets of Oakland,
芝加哥街道等地都有闹事
or they do in the streets of Chicago!
能进去吗？
Can I come in?
来这里对你没有益处
It's not good for you to be here.
为什么？
Why?
丑恶
It's ugly.
整件事非常丑恶
This whole thing is so ugly.
接受这一切会象什么？
Have you any idea what it's like to live with all this?
人们看我们 只看到顽固分子和种族主义者
People look at us and only see bigots and racists.
仇恨并不是天生的
Hatred isn't something you're born with.
是教导的
It gets taught.
在学校他们说种族隔离圣经里有
At school, they said segregation's what said in the Bible.
创世纪九章 二十七节
Genesis 9, verse 27.
七岁时
At seven years of age,
就被告之 就相信
you get told it enough times, you believe it.
相信仇恨
You believe the hatred.
经历仇恨 发出仇恨
You live it. You breathe it.
嫁给仇恨
You marry it.
那晚我丈夫驾驶其中一辆车
My husband drove one of the cars that night.
- 嘘  - 这就是你想知道的 不是吗？
- Shh  - That's what you wanted to hear, isn't it?
尸体被埋在罗伯茨农场
The bodies are buried on the Roberts' Farm
一个土坝里
in an earthen dam.
长官
Sir.
休息一下 伯德先生
Take a break, Mr. Bird.
用手绢擦擦脸
Put some handkerchiefs around your faces.
今天下午发现三个民权工作者的尸体
The bodies of the three missing civil rights workers were discovered this afternoon
是在一座未公开的墓地
at an undisclosed grave.
FBI和警长处都未对此事作评论
Neither the FBI nor the Sheriff's department will comment on the case.
尸体被带到杰瑟普县医院
The bodies have been brought here to Jessup County Hospital,
官方也拒绝发表评论
where officials have also refused to comment.
据猜测验尸工作将于今晚稍后进行
There is speculation that there will be an autopsy performed later tonight.
让开
Keep it open.
让开路 我们要过去 让开路
Open it up. Coming through. Open it up.
退回去
Hold it back.
克林顿 有问题回家去处理吧
Clinton, you got some problems at home you need to tend to.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我的意思是蠢蛋快滚回去吧
I mean pull your head out of your ass and get home!
我 文森特·汤普森
I, Vincent Thompson,
是切达干酪世界冠军
am the cheddar cheese champion of the world.
在四十二个参赛者的国际竞赛中
In international competition with 42 other entries,
我的切达干酪赢得一等奖
my cheddar won first prize based on flavor,
主要是基于味道 质地 外观和颜色
texture, appearance, and color.
从十七岁开始 我就是一个领有执照的干酪制作者
I've been a liscenced cheesemaker since I was 17 years old.
克林顿 我不期望你这么早回家
Clinton, I didn't expect you home so early.
喂 弗兰克
Hi, Frank.
很抱歉
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
长官
Sir.
再说一遍？
Say again.
我马上就到
I'll be right there.
- 伯德先生  - 怎么？长官
- Mr. Bird.  - Yes, sir?
找五个人到外面见我
Get five men and meet me outside.
安德森在哪里？
Where's Anderson?
他在汽车旅馆 先生
He's at the motel, sir.
你俩去前门
You two take the front door.
别让任何人通过
If anyone tries to get past you, break them down.
你俩去走廊大门
You two take the door on the corridor.
- 伯德先生  - 先生？
- Mr. Bird.  - Sir?
去找安德森 把他带来
Okay. Go get Anderson. Bring him here.
别告诉他为何 什么也别说 只叫他来这里
Don't tell him why, don't tell him anything. Just get him here.
安德森先生 站住
Mr. Anderson, stop!
- 安德森先生  - 滚开
- Mr. Anderson!  - Go to hell.
我叫你站住 我说真的
I'm telling you to stop and I mean it.
我们不是凶手
We're not killers.
这是他们和我们之间的事
That's the difference between them and us.
是他们和你之间的事
That's the difference between them and you!
你比我更不喜欢他们
You're not anymore like them than I am.
错了 你在乎隐藏在警长徽章后面的混蛋？
Wrong! What do you care what I do to some son of a bitch hiding behind a Sheriff's badge?
你要改变整个世界？
Don't you have the whole world to change?
是的 我正在改变
That's right. And I'm changing it.
傲慢自大的笨蛋
You're just as arrogant as you are stupid!
你也在改变世界
You're changing it, too.
该死的 我现在就做一些改变
Hot damn, I'm gonna make some changes right now.
不要这么蠢 别把事搞得一团糟
Don't be so stupid. Don't go messing this up,
因为别人会看你笑话的
just because you're patrial fooling around with witnesses.
你
You!
枪不意味着麻烦 除非你使用
It don't mean shit to have a gun unles you're ready to use it.
你不听我的 我就杀了你
I'll kill you righ tnow, if you don't listen to what I have to tell you.
去你的
Fuck you!
我走
Let me go.
我们一起去
We'll go after all of them, together.
你不知道如何
You wouldn't know how.
你教我
You're gonna teach me how.
你没有胆量
You don't have the guts.
我不但有胆量 我还有权力
Not only do I have the guts, I have the authority!
那意味着什么？
What does that's supposed to mean?
新规则
New rules.
按我们的方式起诉他们 也是你的方式
We nail them any way we can. Even your way.
这是你说的还是有些家伙在暗中操纵你？
Is this you talking or some guy's pulling your strings, huh?
两者
Both.
- 我们按我的方式做  - 你的方式
- We do it my way!  - Your way.
- 用我的人  - 不惜一切
- With my people!  - Whatever it takes.
好
Okay.
给我一分钟
Give me a minute.
你认为他会向我开枪吗？
You think he would have shot me?
会 长官
Oh, yes, sir.
他是一个有种的小混蛋
He's a ballsy little bastard, isn't he?
他们想要我说“我们不要忘记那两个白人男孩也死于
They want me to say let us not forget that two white boys also died
帮助黑人”
helping Negroes help themselves.
他们想要我说
They want me to say
“我们与两个白人男孩的母亲一起悲痛”
we mourn with the mothers of these two white boys.
但是密西西比州
But the State of Mississippi
甚至不许这两个白人男孩与那个黑人男孩葬在相同的公墓里
won't even allow these white boys to be buried in the same cemetery as this Negro boy.
我没有更多的爱奉献
I say, I have no more love to give.
今天 我心中只有怒火 我想要你们和我一起愤怒
I have only anger in my heart today, and I want you to be angry with me!
现在 我烦恼 我厌倦 我想要你们和我一起烦恼 厌倦
I am sick, and I am tired, and I want you to be sick and tired with me!
我烦恼 我厌倦参加黑人的葬礼
I am sick and tired of going to the funerals of black men,
他是被白人谋杀的
who have been murdered by white men.
我烦恼 我厌倦这片国土的人民
I am sick and tired of the people of this country,
他们继续纵容着这些事的发生
who continue to allow these things to happen.
如果你是一个黑人 什么是“不可剥夺的权利”？
What is an "unalienable right", if you are a Negro?
什么是“依法获得平等待遇”？
What does it mean "equal treatment under the law"?
什么是“自由和公平”？
What does it mean "liberty and justice for all"?
我对这些人说 看这个年轻人的脸
Now I say to these people, look at the face of this young young man
你将看到一个黑人的脸
and you will see the face of a black man.
如果你看那鲜血 是红的
But if you look at the blood shed, it is red!
就象你的 和你的一样
It is like yours! It is just like yours!
你…
You...
我说一个故事
I'm gonna tell you a story.
一个叫霍默·威尔克斯的孩子住在离这以北三十里
A young kid named Homer Wilkes, lives about 30 miles north of here.
他带着他的女友回家 正沿着道路往回走
He'd just taken his girlfriend home and was walking back along the road,
一辆汽车停下来
when a car pulled up.
三个白人男孩把他抓上车
Three white boys took him for a ride.
然而
Now,
他没做任何事情
he hadn't done anything
只不过
except
是一个黑人
be a Negro.
他们带他到一间小屋
And they took him to a shack.
象这样的一间小屋
A shack like this one.
他们取出一块刀片
They took out a razor blade.
象这样的一块平常的旧刀片
Regular razor blade like this one.
他们扯开他的裤子
They pulled down his pants,
分开他的腿
they spread his legs
切掉他的阴囊
and they sliced off his scrotum.
放进一个咖啡杯
Put it in a coffee cup.
你知道切断你的阴囊会出多少血吗？
Do you know how much you bleed when somebody cuts off your balls?
啊？
Huh? !
人们找到霍默时 他们说
When they found Homer they said he looked like
他的腰以下就象被浸在血液中
he'd been dipped in blood up to his waist.
人们把他送到医院时 他还勉强活着
He was barely alive when they got him to the hospital.
现在他几乎不能行走
He can hardly walk now.
市长 我们知道你清楚
Mayor, we know you know who was there
三个民权男孩被杀害时 谁在场
when those three civil rights boys were murdered.
我们知道你清楚谁扣了扳机
We know you know who pulled the trigger.
还有什么要说的吗？
Is there something you wanna say to me?
好了
Okay.
他与调查局一致吗？
Is he with the Bureau?
嗯 他相当于一位专家
Yeah, he's kind of a specialist.
你相信市长不会讲吗？
You're sure the mayor won't talk about any of this?
不会 他们会杀了他
No, they'd kill him.
- 好吧 有什么收获？ - 额…
- All right, what do you have?  - Well...
三辆车 七个人
It was three cars, seven men involved.
佩尔和贝利开的枪
Pell and Bailey, they did the killing.
斯塔基警长呢？
Sheriff Stuckey?
他太精明了 所以没去 因此佩尔为他扣扳机
He knew about it, but he's too smart to be there. So Pell pulled the trigger for him.
汤利呢？
And Townley?
是他的主意
It was his idea.
巨龙们不能脏了手
Grand Dragons, they don't get their hands dirty.
整个事情 哼？核心的核心
The whole thing, huh? Bullet by bullet.
我不认为你会对
I don't suppose you're interested in words like
“强制” “谣言” “胁迫”感兴趣
coercion or hearsay or duress?
这在法庭没用
This is no good in court.
我们不在法庭 沃德先生
We're not in court, Mr. Ward.
绝不会因谋杀起诉他们 我们要公诉
We'll never get them on murder anyway. That's a state charge.
- 那些乡巴佬绝不会起诉  - 我知道
- These hastings will never prosecute.  - I know that.
必须在联邦法庭起诉他们
Well, we've got to pick them in Federal Court.
侵犯公民权利
Violation of civil rights!
不要忘记你在侵犯谁的权利
Just don't lose sight of whose rights are violated!
别把我与你扯在一起 沃德先生
Don't put me on your perch, Mr. Ward!
别把我扯进你的阴沟里 安德森先生
Don't drag me into your gutter, Mr. Anderson!
这些人爬出了阴沟 沃德先生
These people crawled out of the sewer, Mr. Ward!
或许我们应该在阴沟
Maybe the gutter's where we should be!
谢谢
Thank you.
要抓紧
This better be important.
究竟谁召集会议？
Who the hell called this meeting?
我们以为是你
We thought you did.
聚会吗？你是笨蛋？
Of this group? Are you stupid?
你没召集？
You didn't call this?
混蛋 不是你 又是谁？
Shit! Then if you didn't call this, who the fuck did?
- 闭嘴  - 现在 等一下
- Shut up!  - Now, wait a minute!
这是某种骗局？
Is this some kind of a bullshit setup?
雷 你确定你没有召集？
Ray, you're sure you didn't call this?
我从我妻子那里得到消息 说是你和克林顿说的
Because I got a note from my wife and it said it was from you and Clinton.
莱斯特 闭嘴
Lester, shut up!
现在 我们全都出去
Now, we're all gonna walk straight out of here
什么也别说
and say nothing.
那意味着什么 莱斯特
That means nothing, Lester.
就是第一个开口的会死
First one who opens his mouth is a dead man.
闭嘴
Shut up!
嘿 克林顿
Hey, Clinton.
克林顿
Clinton?
看起来象响尾蛇开始自相残杀
It looks like the rattlesnakes are starting to commit suicide.
喂 莱斯特
Hi, Lester.
我们带你回家
We'll give you that ride home.
什么？
What?
你说四点半
Well, I know you said 4:30,
但是我们晚了一点 因此…
but we're running a little late, so...
车上见
I'll meet you in the car.
你疯了
You're cracked.
你有二十分零钱吗？
You have change for a $20?
有
Sure.
莱斯特 去车上
Get in the car, Lester.
你很难挖鼻孔了
Else you're gonna have a real hard time picking your nose
一旦我关了这个抽屉
once I've close this drawer shut.
莱斯特 你自己说出来 事情就简单了
Lester, you could make it a whole lot easier on yourself by going on the record right now.
无可奉告
I ain't got nothing to say.
你搞错了 先生
You're barking up the wrong tree, mister.
莱斯特 我告诉你
Lester, I've got to tell you something.
你的同伙都已经说了
We've got you cold. Your buddies've already talked.
你说谎
You're lying.
你有很多麻烦 莱斯特
You're in a lot of trouble, Lester.
我们知道你驾驶第二辆车 绿色卡车
We know you drove the second vehicle, the green truck.
你的同伙说 我回忆下 伯德先生
And your buddy says, refresh my memory here, Mr. Bird.
是 先生“莱斯特·考恩斯把黑人从车上拖下来
Yes, sir. "Lester Cowens dragged the Negro from the car,
踢了他两下 然后开枪打死他”
"kicked him twice in the face and then shot him."
这是他妈的谎言
That's a goddman lie!
是真的 伯德先生 还有什么？
No, it's true. What else you've got in there, Mr. Bird?
“莱斯特·考恩斯说‘只留下黑鬼 至少我射了黑鬼’”
"Lester Cowens then said, 'They only left me a nigger, but at least I shot me a nigger.'"
我没有杀死他 我是朝他屁股开枪
I didn't kill him. I only shot him in the ass.
我们知道 你开枪时 他已经死
We know that. He was already dead by the time you put a slug in him.
但你的同伙不这么认为 你他们认为是你杀的
But your buddy sees it differently. Your buddy tells it that you killed the kid.
你是投案自首
Now either you go on the record for us right now,
还是不只是朝黑人孩子的屁股开枪
or it's gonna be your ass we're talking about, not just a black kid's!
好好想一想 莱斯特
Think about it, Lester.
出去吧
Come on out of there.
去吧
Come on out.
真要技巧
This is tricky.
看起来那么容易 不是吗？
They make it look so easy, don't they?
克林顿 我有一个问题
I got a question for you, Clinton.
叫你克林顿 不介意吧？
You don't mind if I call you Clinton, do you?
我想我非常了解你
I feel like I know you so well.
在凶杀的那晚
The way we have it, on the night of the murders,
在坝上推土机掩埋那些孩子时 你讲了一句话
you made a short speech as the bulldozer buried the kids in the dam.
莱斯特怎样说的？“密西西比将为你感到骄傲
How does Lester tell it? "Mississippi would be proud of you.
你为白人而奋斗”
"You've struck a blow for the white man."
是你说的吗？克林顿
Is that what you said, Clinton?
是你说的吗？一定是你
Is that what you said? It must have been you.
因为克莱顿·汤利和雷·斯塔基不在场
Because Clayton Townley and Ray Stuckey, they were too smart to be there.
你太愚蠢了 没料到有人记得吧
You're too stupid to think anybody would remember what you had to say.
但老莱斯特记忆很好
But old Lester, he got a good memory.
我很抱歉 我很久没这样了
I'm sorry. I haven't done this for a long time.
你有讲吗？
Did you make a speech
在你打你妻子的那晚 克林顿 呵？
the night that you beat up your wife, Clinton? Huh?
你说？
Did you?
你打白人的那晚呢？
Did you strike a blow for the white man that night?
你可知道你有一种傻笑？佩尔
You got a stupid smile. You know that, pal?
你看到了吗？呵
Can you see it? Huh?
推土机辗过黑人孩子时 傻笑了吗？
Did you smile when the bulldozer ran over the black kid's body? Did you?
掩盖那些尸体时 傻笑了吗？
Did you smile when the bodies were covered over?
起来 快起来 起来
Get up here. Come on! Get up here.
你傻笑了吗？你说？
Did you smile that same stupid smile? Huh? Did you?
傻笑了吗？佩尔 笑了吗？
Did you smile, Pell? Did you smile?
没有错吧 副警长
Make no mistake about it, Deputy.
我会切断你的狗头
I'll cut your fucking head clear off
不会在乎那些胡说八道
and not give a shit how it reads in the report sheet.
再吃一口 再吃一口
One more bite. One more bite.
再吃一口 亲爱的 再吃一口
One more bite, darling. One more bite.
莱斯特 怎么了？
Shit, Lester! What the fuck is going on here?
闭嘴 进卧室锁住门
Shut up! You get in the bedroom and lock the door!
别靠近窗子
And stay away from the windows!
该死
Shit!
拜托 拜托 我并没有说你们的事
Please! Please! I didn't say a thing!
我发誓 这是圈套 我并没有说什么
I swear it's a setup! I didn't say nothing!
我什么也没说
Nothing! I didn't say nothing!
我什么都没说
I didn't say nothing!
我什么也没说
你很幸运 我们一直在关注你 莱斯特
You're lucky we've been watching your ass, Lester.
考恩斯先生 你如果自首 我们就会保护你
If you go on the record, Mr. Cowens, we'll give you protection.
否则…
If not...
否则 他们会杀了你
If not, they're gonna kill you anyway.
莱斯特 你需要洗洗
Oh! You need a toilet, Lester.
真的要他死？
Really had him going, huh?
弗兰克·贝利 因侵犯公民权被判10年监禁
莱斯特·考恩斯 被判3年监禁
斯威利先生 我们会结帐
We'll take care of the check for you.
弗洛伊德·斯威利 被判7年监禁
克林顿·佩尔 被判10年监禁
雷·斯塔基警长 无罪释放
韦斯利·库克 被判7年监禁
克莱顿·汤利 被判10年监禁
他为什么这样做？
Why did he do it?
他甚至没有涉及
He wasn't even in on it.
他甚至不是三K党
He wasn't even Klan.
伯德先生 他有罪
Mr. Bird, he was guilty.
不能只看表面 要看实质
Anyone's guilty who watches this happen and pretends it isn't.
不 他有罪 对吧
No, he was guilty, all right.
就象扣扳机的那些狂热者一样有罪
Just as guilty as the fanatics who pulled the trigger.
也许我们都有罪
Maybe we all are.
有人吗
Hello?
在这里
Yeah.
在医院没见到你 他们说你回家了
I just missed you at the hospital. They said you'd gone home.
怎么能舍弃这里
What's left of it.
非常抱歉
I'm real sorry.
我也抱歉
So am I.
有什么打算？
What are you gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
你要去哪里？
Where will you go?
我哪里也不去 我要留下来
I'm not going anywhere. I'm staying.
这是我的家 我在这里出生
This is my home. Born here.
或许死在这里
Probably die here.
要离开的话 很久以前就离开了
If I wanted to leave, I would've done it a long time ago.
凡事总可以解决
Things will work out.
大家都知道我做得对
There's enough people around here know what I did was right.
很多女士喜欢我理头发的方式
And enough ladies like the way I fix their hair.
嘿
Hey.
即使你永远在得梅因 也别寄明信片给我
If you're ever in Des Moines, don't send me a postcard.
没问题
Ok
♫ 我们见不到 ♫
♪ We cannot see ♪
♫ 在未来 ♫
♪ In the future ♪
♫ 不 不 ♫
♪ No, no, no, no, no ♪
♫ 很难 ♫
♪ And it's hard ♪
♫ 微笑着 ♫
♪ To smile ♪
♫ 通过考验 ♫
♪ Through trials ♪
♫ 不 我们 ♫
♪ No we ♪
♫ 见不到 ♫
♪ cannot see ♪
♫ 每个陷阱 ♫
♪ Every pitfall ♪
♫ 我们必须继续前行 ♫
♪ But we must walk on ♪
♫ 信仰 ♫
♪ By faith ♪
♫ 每一天 哦 上帝 ♫
♪ Each day oh, Lord! ♪
♫ 哇 星期一 ♫
♪ Woah, on Monday ♪
♫ 继续前行 ♫
♪ Walk on ♪
♫ 星期二 ♫
♪ And on Tuesday ♪
♫ 继续前行 ♫
♪ Walk on ♪
♫ 哇 跟随耶稣 ♫
♪ Woah, let Jesus be ♪
♫ 让他成为你的 ♫
♪ Let me him be ♪
♫ 你的向导 ♫
♪ Your guide ♪
♫ 喔哦 ♫
♪ Whoo-oo-oo ♪
♫ 他能 ♫
♪ He's able ♪
♫ 他能肩负你的重任 ♫
♪ He can carry your load ♪
♫ 他能看清前行的方向 ♫
♪ And he can see way down the road ♪
♫ 继续前行 ♫
♪ Walk on by faith ♪
你想开车吗？鲁珀特
You wanna drive, Rupert?
嗯
Yeah.
♫ 星期一 ♫
♪ Woah, on Monday ♪
♫ 继续前行 ♫
♪ Walk on ♪
♫ - 星期二  - 继续前行 ♫
♪ - And on Tuesday  - Walk on ♪
♫ 跟随耶稣 ♫
♪ Let Jesus be ♪
♫ - 让他成为你的  - 你的向导 ♫
♪ - Let him be your  - Your guide ♪
♫ - 他能  - 肩负你的重任 ♫
♪ - He's able  - To carry your load ♪
♫ 肩负你的重任 ♫
♪ To carry your load♪
♫ 他能看清前行的方向 ♫
♪ And he can see way down the road ♪
♫ 继续前行 ♫
♪ Walk on ♪